MARCO LAM

Maynooth, Co. Kildare, Ireland

📕 +353 876667840 | 🔀 marcohoucheng@gmail.com | 🛠 marcohoucheng.github.io | 🖸 marcohoucheng | 🛅 marcohoucheng

Introduction_

As an Irish MSc student in Computer Science with a mathematics undergraduate background, I enjoy tackling difficult problems. I have industry experience as a Data Engineer. I am passionate in data-driven technology, specifically in Computer Vision and Deep Learning models. I want to use my creativity and problem solving abilities to be at the forefront of new innovation.

Education

University of Padova Padova, Italy

MSc Computer Science

Oct 2022 - July 2024

- Grade: Exp. 110/110 Laude, equiv. to $\mathbf{1}^{\text{st}}$ Class Honours
- Thesis Algorithmic Approach to 15 Minute City
- Courses: Concurrency & Distribution, Functional Languages, Deep Learning, Computer Vision, Advanced Algorithms, Data Mining, Mobile Programming, Big Data Computing

University College Dublin

Dublin, Ireland

MSc Data & Computational Science - GPA:3.99

Sept 2019 - Sept 2020

- **Grade:** 1st Class Honours
- Courses: Data Programming with C, R & Python, Statistical Network Analysis, High Performance Computing, Bayesian Analysis, Stochastic Models, Machine Learning, Numerical Algorithms

BSc Financial Mathematics - GPA: 3.45

Sept 2015 - May 2019

- Grade: Upper 2nd Class (2.1) Honours
- Research Internship: Latent Position Models
- Courses: Cryptography, Time Series, Bayesian Models, Partial Differential Equations, Linear Models, Complex Analysis, Groups, Rings and Fields, Metric Spaces

Thesis

Algorithmic Approach to 15 Minute City

MSc Thesis - github.com/marcohoucheng/Algorithmic-Approach-to-15-Minute-City

Jan 2024 - Jul 2024

- Provide a generalised approach to determine the "15-Minute City" in any given map or city.
- Aim to design an efficient algorithm to improve on the existing solutions in literature.
- Adapt and modify popular graph search algorithms to minimise complexity such as Dijkstra's and Johnson's algorithm.
- The proposed solution will be implemented in Rust as a showcase to the theory.
- Technical Skills: Rust, Python, Graph Search

Skills_

Programming Python, Rust, C, C++, F#, Java, Swift, Go, Javascript, SQL, VBA, R, Matlab

Frameworks Pytorch, Tensorflow, PySpark, AWS

Languages English (Fluent), Cantonese Chinese (Fluent), Mandarin Chinese (Fluent) and Italian (A1).

Work Experience __

Allied Irish Banks (AIB)

Data Engineer

Dublin, Ireland

Sept 2020 - Sept 2022

• Developed and managed Teradata Data Warehouse along with Microsoft SQL Server databases.

- Automated SQL ETL pipelines to generate risk assessments and regulatory reports for business teams.
- Performed A/B testing, investigated and resolved any data quality issues.
- Replicated errors found in workflows through SQL Server Management Studio and pivot tables.
- Created, reviewed and updated procedure documents for future references and provided training to new members.

University College Dublin

Dublin, Ireland

Research Intern - github.com/marcohoucheng/Research-in-Latent-Position-Models

June 2019 - Aug 2019

- Research project focused on Latent Position Models supervised by Dr. Riccardo Rastelli.
- Simulated social-connection models on R using Monte-Carlo Markov Chains.
- · Applied Game Theory and Bayes Risks Theory to compare and optimise statistical models.
- Revised and improved algorithms to boost performance and reduce computational costs to optimisation tools.

Private Tutor Dublin, Ireland

Leaving Certificate Tutor

Sept 2017 - June 2019

- Tutored for both ordinary and higher level Leaving Certificate Mathematics.
- Taught higher level Applied Mathematics as an extra subject outside of school.
- Identified the needs of the students and developed academic strategies.
- · Prepared weekly plans and materials and communicated with parents to check in on the students' progress.

Projects_

Brain Tumour Segmentation Prediction

github.com/marcohoucheng/Brain-Tumor-Segmentation-with-Computer-Vision

Feb 2024 - Apr 2024

- A pipeline computer vision deep learning model with a Convolutional-Autoencoder and a U-Net model.
- Identify the region and segmentation of brain tumours through MRI scans.
- Achieved a test accuracy of 98%.
- Technical Skills: Python with Pytorch, cv2, pandas, multiprocessing libraries

ML Interpreter

github.com/marcohoucheng/ML-Interpreter

Oct 2022 - Jan 2023

- An interpreter for a ML functional language following theoretical typing and evaluation rules.
- Implemented with a type inference mechanism to ensure absolute type safety within expressions.
- Developed comprehensive understanding of the functioning of programming language compilers.
- Technical Skills: F#, functional languages

Gran Turismo 7 Price Tracker

github.com/marcohoucheng/Gran-Turismo-7-Price-Tracker

Dec 2023 - Mar 2024

- Aimed to create a solution without the requirement of creating accounts on existing services.
- Automated email service to notify dynamic in-game information updates in HTML format.
- Streamlined process to create and update local databases with a scheduled web-scraper.
- Technical Skills: Python with pandas, urllib, smtplib, ssl and more

Computer Vision and Deep Learning Projects

github.com/marcohoucheng/Computer-Vision-and-Deep-Learning

Aug 2023 - Dec 2024

- · A series of Python Notebooks showcasing studies of various computer vision and deep learning topics.
- · Models implemented including SIFT, Bag of Words, CNN, Recurrent Neural Networks, LSTM, GRU, Transformers and more.
- Utilising pre-trained models such as AlexNet, GoogLeNet and ResNet.
- Technical Skills: Python with Pytorch, pandas, cv2 and more

Academic Achievements

Scholarship, Education and Youth Affairs Bureau Macau	2016,2018
2^{nd} in Mathematical Olympiad Contest at Maynooth University	2015
All Ireland Linguistics Olympiad Final Competition at Dublin City University	2015
Irish Applied Mathematics Team Quiz National Final	2014

Certificates ____

Amazon AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner	2022
Bloomberg Market Concept	2018

Interests ____

Outdoor activities Causal tennis player, I also enjoy cycling and hiking

Motor RacingI love the racing and the engineering development of different categories including Formula 1 and WEC **Technology**Interested in the latest technology development especially in computer hardware and OSes